(AS) Amit Shrestha

424 958 951 | **E:** amitshrestha37@gmail.com 15A Louisa Street, Auburn, NSW 2144 www.amitshrestha.me | linkedin.com/in/mrtordoide | twitter.com/mrtordoide

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, passionate, hardworking and motivated candidate currently pursuing Bachelor of Information Technology in web development with expert understanding of various programming languages. Looking forward to join an organization where the opportunity for professional growth and personal development is embraced.

SOFT SKILLS •

- Self-motivated
- Public speaking
- Powerful negotiator
- Extremely organized

- Team leadership
- Quick learner
- Interpersonal and written communication

HARD SKILLS O

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, PHP, C#, HTML/CSS, JavaScript and more.
- Technologies: Linux/Windows/MacOS, Wordpress, Joomla, Git, Bash, ASP.NET MVC and more.
- Free and Open Source Technology and *nix.

WORK HISTORY

IHELPER

11/2018 to CURRENT

Victoria University Sydney | Sydney, NSW

- Assist the IT Department during their off hours.
- Provide IT support to the VU Sydney Academic staffs and Students as well.
- Assist students as well as teachers at VUS with Office 365, MyVU Portal,
 Printings and other application software.

STUDENT MENTOR TEAM LEADER

10/2018 to CURRENT

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus | Sydney, NSW

- Help new students to transition through their first days at University by sharing own knowledge and experiences.
- Assist new as well as old students in orientation sessions and enrollments.
- Supervised Student Mentors in different sections through out VU Sydney enrollment process to provide assistance during enrollments and solve general student inquiry.

ACADEMIC TUTOR, BACHELOR OF IT

07/2018 to CURRENT

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus | Sydney, NSW

- Provided early intervention assistance to struggling students.
- Responded to email and telephone requests for assistance with specific questions.
- Offered complete instructional support for students unable to attend regular classes.

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

02/2017 to 07/2017

Roshan Labs Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Bagmati

- Built website interfaces with HTML and CSS.
- Applied knowledge of JavaScript and Object-Oriented Programming to create fulfil customer requirements.
- Designed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Firefox,
 Chrome and Safari.

EDUCATION \circ

Bachelor | Information Technology

08/2019

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus, Sydney, NSW

- Doing Major in Mobile and Web Application Development
- Doing Minor in **Network Management**

High School Certificate | Science with Computer Science National School of Science, Kathmandu, Central Development Region

School Leaving Certificate

Daisy English Boarding Secondary School, Khairahani, Central Development Region

TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Micro Course Critical Thinking and Problem Solving. <u>View:</u> http://bit.ly/32yckgx
- Developing IoT Solutions using Azure and Windows 10 training organised by Microsoft Innovation Centre, Nepal. <u>View:</u> https://goo.gl/v7WQFB
- Science and Robotics Workshop 2016 organized by Kalinga Science Center. View: http://bit.ly/2Ssu4Fk
- Microsoft Office 2013 Specialist [MS WORD] Certification. <u>View:</u> <u>https://goo.gl/Lc3uCw</u>

VOLUNTEERING OEXPERIENCES

- Intermediate Student Partner [ISP] for Microsoft Innovation Centre, Nepal for year 2016/17.
- Organizer of Software Freedom Day 2016, Nepal. <u>View: https://foss-np.github.io/sfd-2016/sfdteam.html</u>

- Volunteer, Exhibitor at Computer Association of Nepal [CAN] InfoTech
 2016, Nepal for FOSS Nepal Community. <u>View: https://goo.gl/dWx5RF</u>
- Organizer and Speaker in various sessions of Pre-Software Freedom Day 2016 Events.
- Organizer of Software Freedom Day 2015, Nepal. <u>View:</u> <u>https://goo.gl/24jknD</u>
- Volunteer and Contact Person at Free and Open Source Software [FOSS] Nepal Community since 2015. <u>View: https://goo.gl/uBx4Ax</u>